

A self-motivated developer with 2+ years of experience in a fast-paced leading educational startup and continuously striving to expand skill sets. Proficient in Python/Django and learning new programming languages like Golang. Aspiring to be part of a team that solves problems using technology and learn new things. Have a bachelor's degree in Computer Science.

Technical Skills_

Operating Systems GNU/Linux (Ubuntu, Arch Linux), Windows

Programming Python, Go(Basics),

Web HTML, CSS

Frameworks Django, Flask(Basics)

Version Control System Git

Experience ____

Entri.me Ernakulam, Kerala

PRODUCT ENGINEER Feb. 2015 - Present

Feb.n2015 the esignate employees

· Designed a payment processing system and integrated with Payumoney and Razorpay for processing the payments

- Integrated with SendGrid for transactional emails and Mvaayoo for transactional SMS
- Designed and implemented REST APIs to support entri.me Android Application
- Developed responsive web applications with Bootstrap and Sass preprocessor
- Created dashboard to track and analyse student performance for teachers

Recursive Labs Ernakulam, Kerala

SOFTWARE TRAINEE March. 2014 - Jan. 2015

Febsed & ND/Esept Operating System from day 1 and did Python based projects and programming assignments.

• Gained exposure in developing web applications using Python based frameworks like Django and Flask

Projects

Mvaayoo Python

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JOSEJIBIN/MVAAYOO-PYTHON

• Python wrapper around Mvaayoo API

URL Shortener

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JOSEJIBIN/URL-SHORTENER

- A simple URL shortener application
- Written using the Django framework
- · Ability to create custom short URLs

Hercule

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JOSEJIBIN/HERCULE

- A minimalist, responsive, and open-source theme for Hugo, a fast static site generator built with GoLang
- A minimal blog theme
- Built-in support for 404 pages, Disqus comments, and Google Analytics.

Volunteer Experience _____

Django Girls Workshop

Содсн

Django Girls is a community that empowers and helps women to organize free, one-day programming workshop for 30-60 people about building their first application using HTML, CSS, Python and Django.

coached Django Girls Thiruvananthapuram event organized by students from LBSITW

Education.

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

Mar. 2009 - 2013

• Organised inter college computer science fest